While viewing message definitions and topic information can be informative,
查看消息定义和主题消息会很有帮助
sometimes the best way to understand what is going on is to look
有时候 要了解当前情况
at the messages themselves as they are published to a topic.
最好的方式是查看发布到主题的消息本身
For example, when the turtle rotates left and
例如 当乌龟向左和向右旋转时
right which axis is it actually rotating about?
实际上是围绕哪个轴旋转？
And what are the units of rotation?
旋转单位是什么？
And are rotations expressed in terms of radians or degrees?
旋转是使用弧度耗时度数表示的？
To get the answer to these questions,
要知道这些问题的答案
You can use the command rostopic echo.
你可以使用 rostopic echo 命令
Let's dive right into its usage.
我们来看下具体用法
Rostopic, echo,
Rostopic、echo
and then the name of the topic forward
然后是主题名称 斜线
slash turtle one forward slash command underscore vel.
Turtle 斜线 command 下划线 vel
If you've forgotten the name of the topic,
如果你忘了主题名称
you can easily find it by using
有个办法很简单
the command rostopic list which you were introduced to earlier in the screentask.
使用你之前的 screentask 里学到的 rostopic list 命令
When you hit enter, the terminal cursor will move to a new line
点击回车键 终端光标或移动到新的一行
and it will appear as though nothing has happened. Fear not though.
看上去好像没任何变化 但别担心
Rostopic echo is simply waiting for a message to be published on the command vel topic.
Rostopic echo 只是在等待消息发布在 command vel 主题上
In order to publish a message to the topic,
要向主题发布一条消息
we must jump all the way back to the console window for
我们必须跳回控制台窗口
the turtle underscore teleop underscore key node.
找到 turtle 下划线 telecop 下划线 key 节点
And I'm now going to hit the left arrow key.As expected,
我点击向左的箭头 和预料的一样
the turtle turned counter-clockwise by some angle for about one second.
乌龟以某个角度顺时针旋转大约 1 秒钟
I'd estimate that the actual number is somewhat maybe like greater than 90 degrees,
我估计 实际数字可能超过了 90 度
but perhaps less than 135 degrees.
但应该不到 135 度
Let's go back to the rostopic echo terminal and see what happened.
我们回到 rostopic echo 终端 看看会发生什么
And as you can see we've caught a message.
你可以看到 我们捕捉到了一条消息
All of the velocity components are zero with
所有速度分量都是零
the exception of the z component of the angular velocity.
唯一的例外是角速度的 z 分量
Here we see a value of two.
这里 我们看到值是 2
This tells us, that when the turtle rotates counterclockwise,
这告诉我们 当乌龟逆时针旋转时
it is doing so around the z axis.
它是围绕 z 轴旋转的
The magnitude of the velocity,
速度的量级告诉我们
tells us that the units associated with the movement are
和运动相关联的单位
probably in radians per second. How did I get there?
很可能是弧度每秒 这是怎么得到的呢
Well, a quick math check will tell us that two radians corresponds to
做个快速匹配 即可得知 两个弧度
approximately 114.6 degrees. And there we have it.
对应的大约是 114.6 度 就在这里
You should now have some understanding about rostopic echo and
现在 你应该对 rostopic echo 有所了解
how it can be used for investigating messages passing over a topic.
并知道如何使用它来研究在主题上传递的消息了
As a side note, If this unit's investigation seems a little bit contrived,
另外说一下 如果这个单位有点不太自然
that's because it certainly was.
那是因为它本来就这样
Like any sensible engineers,
和所有理性的工程师一样
the developers of Ros have elected to standardize around S-I units wherever applicable.
ROS 的开发者选择了尽可能使用国际标准单位
Which is to say, length is measured in meters.
也就是说 长度的单位是米
Mass is measured in kilograms,
质量单位是千克
time is measured in seconds and angles are measured in radians and so on.
时间单位是秒 角度单位是弧度 等等
You've now completed a brief tour of the Ros command line tools.
现在 你已经大致了解了 ROS 命令行工具
Armed with this knowledge and
利用这些知识
the general understanding of the Ros communications architecture,
结合你对 ROS 通信架构的一般了解
you should be prepared to move on to the next
你已经可以继续下一个步骤了
step - setting up your first catkin workspace.
设置你的第一个 catkin 工作空间